Guide to the David S. Brown papers, 1915-1989 MS0001.UA
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Miscellaneous articles and manuscripts, MS0001 Series 7; 3.5 Linear feet (Box 35, Box 34, Box 33, Box 32, Box 31, Box 30, Box 36)
  - Some Quotations Having To Do With the Human Factor, undated (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Quotations, undated (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Some Quotes On Organizations, undated (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Systems, undated (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Some Quotes On Bureaucracy, undated (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - Policy: What It Is And Who Makes It, undated (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - Some Quotations Having To Do With Power And Authority, undated (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - Some Quotes On Leadership, undated (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - Some Quotations Having To Do With Public Administration, undated (Box 31, Folder 12)
  - Public Opinion, undated (Box 31, Folder 13)
  - Politics, undated (Box 31, Folder 14)
  - Presidents, undated (Box 31, Folder 15)
  - Congress, undated (Box 31, Folder 16)
  - Military, undated (Box 31, Folder 17)
  - Some Quotations Having To Do With Development And Development Administration, undated (Box 31, Folder 18)
  - Work and Science, undated (Box 31, Folder 19)
  - Education, undated (Box 31, Folder 20)
  - Wisdom, undated (Box 31, Folder 21)
  - Wit, undated (Box 31, Folder 22)
  - Riposte and Miscellany, undated (Box 31, Folder 23)
  - Papers (DSB), undated (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Papers (DSB), undated (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Manuscripts, undated (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - DSB-Papers, undated (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - DSB/GWU Records (Misc. Manuscripts), undated (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Evaluations of D.S.B. (GWU-Reports), undated (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Family, etc., undated (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Old Papers (Misc.), undated (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - DSB Citations, undated (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Medical, undated (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - GWU Correspondence, 1984-1987 (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - History of School of Government and Business Administration (misc.), undated (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - Evaluations of D.S.B. (GWU-Reports), undated (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - Evaluations of D.S.B. (GWU-Reports), undated (Box 33, Folder 10)
  - Permanent Records (D.S.B.-Perm. Records) [Aviation log], undated (Box 33, Folder 11)
  - Permanent Records (D.S.B.-Perm. Records), undated (Box 33, Folder 12)
  - DSB (Misc.), undated (Box 33, Folder 13)
  - Envelope with newspaper clippings and pages from DSB's flight class yearbook, undated (Box 33, Folder 14)
  - "Of Pith and Vinegar" (dup.), "The Selection and Development of Senior Executives in Developing Countries", undated (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - "You Can't Get There From Here", undated (Box 35, Folder 1)
    Duplicate
  - Duplicate articles (photocopies), 1953 (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Duplicate articles (photocopies), 1955 (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - Duplicate articles (photocopies), 1956 (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - Duplicate articles (photocopies), 1957 (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - Duplicate articles (photocopies), 1959 (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - Duplicate articles (photocopies), 1960 (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - Duplicate articles (photocopies), 1961 (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - Brown, Dr. David S: Collections, undated (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - Bound volume (duplicate articles), undated (Box 36, Folder 9)
  - Bound volume (duplicate articles), undated (Box 36, Folder 10)
  - Bound volume-DSB Papers (duplicate articles), undated (Box 36, Folder 11)
  - Bound volume (duplicate articles), undated (Box 36, Folder 12)
  - The Public Advisory Board in the Federal Government: An Administrative Analysis of Several Boards with Particular Attention to the Public Advisory Board of the Economic Cooperation Administration and the Mutual Security Program, 1936 (Box 36, Folder 13)
    Dissertation of David S. Brown
- Memorabilia, 1954-1986; MS0001 Series 8; 1.5 Linear feet (Box 37)
  This series contains plaques, diplomas, and certificates from David S. Brown's career. It also includes the typewriter on which he typed his doctoral dissertation and his cap and gown.
  - Plaque-Certificate of Appreciation from the School of Government and Business Administration, 11/30/1984 (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Plaque-Distinguished Service Award from the School of Government and Business Administration, 05/04/1986 (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - Plaque-Outstanding Author: The Manager's Responsibilities for Productivity Improvement from the Quarterly Professional Journal of the American Society of Military Comptrollers, 1983 (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - Plaque-The George Washington University with grateful appreciation hereby recognizes Dr. David S. Brown as a member of the Luther Rice Society, 1979 (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - Framed painting, bottom reads "To David S. Brown with affectionate regards, Louis Brownlow", undated (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - Framed photograph-Signed at bottom: "With Best Wishes DW Bree, 10-22-54", 10/22/1954 (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - Framed ink caricature of David S. Brown-"David" written in upper left-hand corner, undated (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - Framed diploma to David S. Brown from the Academia del Mediterraneo. In Italian., undated (Box 37, Folder 8)
  - Unframed certificate-Management Achievement Award from Washington Chapter Society for Advancement of Management, 1968 (Box 37, Folder 9)
  - Unframed Certificate of Appreciation from School of Government and Business Administration, 05/06/1979 (Box 37, Folder 10)
  - Memorabilia (Box NOT SPECIFIED)
  - Remington manual typewriter (Box NOT SPECIFIED, Folder 1)
    Used by Dr. Brown to write Ph.D. thesis. Added to collectionas donatin from his widow Anne Brown, March 2002.
  - David S. Brown's Caps and Gown, undated (Box 98, Folder 1)
    Formerly ACC#673; on display in David S. Brown Memorabilia Room
- Personal papers, 1936-1988; MS0001 Series 9; 1.5 Linear feet (Box 39)
  This series contains personal information on David S. Brown, including biographical/genealogical information, a yearbook, a dissertation and thesis, drafts of novels, and travelogues.
  The materials range from 1936-88.
  - Personal Papers (Box 39)
  - Personal Papers: Biographical data, genealogy, medical, "The Six Wise Men," etc., undated (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Personal Papers:Biographical data, genealogy, medical, "The Six Wise Men," etc., undated (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - Personal Papers:Biographical data, genealogy, medical, "The Six Wise Men," etc., undated (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Personal Papers:Biographical data, genealogy, medical, "The Six Wise Men," etc., undated (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - Personal Papers:University of Maine yearbook, 1936 (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - Personal Papers:David Brown's dissertation, "The Public Advisory Board in the Federal Government," Syracuse University, 1954. (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - Personal Papers:Thesis Brown directed while at GW by Clinton Britt, 1966 (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - Personal Papers:"Writings on Maine", undated (Box 39, Folder 8)
  - Personal Papers:Draft of novel titled "Death Makes the Deadline", undated (Box 39, Folder 9)
  - Personal Papers:Draft of novel titled "A Family Affair", undated (Box 39, Folder 10)
  - Personal Papers:Travelogues of Brown, 1962-1988 ca. (Box 39, Folder 11)
  - Personal Papers:Travelogues of Brown, 1962-1988 ca. (Box 39, Folder 12)
  - Personal Papers:Travelogues of Brown, 1962-1988 ca. (Box 39, Folder 13)
- Professional writings, ca.1955-1990; MS0001 Series 10; 7.5 Linear feet (Box 41, Box 42, Box 39, Box 40, Box 43, Box 44)
  This series includes drafts, articles, quotations, and correspondence with publishers, from about 1955-90.
  - Professional Writings, undated (Box 39)
  - Professional Writings: Correspondence with publishers and published articles, 1955-1990 ca. (Box 39, Folder 14)
  - Professional Writings:Correspondence with publishers and published articles, 1955-1990 ca. (Box 39, Folder 15)
  - Professional Writings:Correspondence with publishers and published articles, 1955-1990 ca. (Box 39, Folder 16)
  - Professional Writings:Correspondence with publishers and published articles, 1955-1990 ca. (Box 39, Folder 17)
  - Professional Writings (Box 40)
  - Professional Writings:Scrapbooks of articles, 1955-1958 (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - Professional Writings:Scrapbooks of articles, 1960-1962 (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - Professional Writings:Scrapbooks of articles, 1963-1964 (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - Professional Writings:Scrapbooks of articles, 1965-1977 (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - Professional Writings:Miscellaneous articles, 1975-1989 (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - Professional Writings:Miscellaneous articles, 1975-1989 (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - Professional Writings:Miscellaneous articles, 1975-1989 (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - Professional Writings:Miscellaneous articles, 1975-1989 (Box 40, Folder 8)
  - Professional Writings (Box 41)
  - Professional Writings:Miscellaneous articles, 1975-1989 (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Professional Writings:Miscellaneous articles, 1975-1989 (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Professional Writings:Miscellaneous articles, 1975-1989 (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - Professional Writings:Miscellaneous articles, 1975-1989 (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - Professional Writings:Book draft "Building a Concept for Action,", 1988 ca. (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - Professional Writings:Book draft "Building a Concept for Action,", 1988 ca. (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - Professional Writings:Articles on management and management techniques, 1970-1990 ca. (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - Professional Writings:Articles on management and management techniques, 1970-1990 ca. (Box 41, Folder 8)
  - Professional Writings:Articles on management and management techniques, 1970-1990 ca. (Box 41, Folder 9)
  - Professional Writings:Articles on management and management techniques, 1970-1990 ca. (Box 41, Folder 10)
  - Professional Writings:Articles on management and management techniques, 1970-1990 ca. (Box 41, Folder 11)
  - Professional Writings:Articles on management and management techniques, 1970-1990 ca. (Box 41, Folder 12)
  - Professional Writings:Articles on management and management techniques, 1970-1990 ca. (Box 41, Folder 13)
  - Professional Writings:Articles on management and management techniques, 1970-1990 ca. (Box 41, Folder 14)
  - Professional Writings:Articles on management and management techniques, 1970-1990 ca. (Box 41, Folder 15)
  - Professional Writings:Articles on management and management techniques, 1970-1990 -- --ca. (Box 41, Folder 16)
  - Professional Writings:Articles on management and management techniques, 1970-1990 ca. (Box 41, Folder 17)
  - Professional Writings:Articles on management and management techniques, 1970-1990 ca. (Box 41, Folder 18)
  - Professional Writings:Articles on management and management techniques, 1970-1990 ca. (Box 41, Folder 19)
  - Professional Writings:Articles on management and management techniques, 1970-1990 ca. (Box 41, Folder 20)
  - Professional Writings:Articles on management and management techniques, 1970-1990 ca. (Box 41, Folder 21)
  - Professional Writings:Articles on management and management techniques, 1970-1990 ca. (Box 41, Folder 22)
  - Professional Writings:Articles on management and management techniques, 1970-1990 ca. (Box 41, Folder 23)
  - Professional Writings (Box 42)
  - Professional Writings:Quotes on management/leadership, undated (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - Professional Writings:Book drafts for "The Year of the Mongoose," and "Seeing it Through," with correspondence with the publisher, 1989 ca. (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Professional Writings:Book drafts for "The Year of the Mongoose," and "Seeing it Through," with correspondence with the publisher, 1989 ca. (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - Professional Writings:Book drafts for "The Year of the Mongoose," and "Seeing it Through," with correspondence with the publisher, 1989 ca. (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - Professional Writings:Book drafts for "The Year of the Mongoose," and "Seeing it Through," with correspondence with the publisher, 1989 ca. (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - Professional Writings:Book drafts for "The Year of the Mongoose," and "Seeing it Through," with correspondence with the publisher, 1989 ca. (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - Professional Writings:Book drafts for "The Year of the Mongoose," and "Seeing it Through," with correspondence with the publisher, 1989 ca. (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - Professional Writings:"Pith and Vinegar" - a collection of epigrams, aphorisms, maxims, proverbs, etc, that Brown wrote over the years, 1984 (Box 42, Folder 8)
  - Professional Writings:"Pith and Vinegar" - a collection of epigrams, aphorisms, maxims, proverbs, etc, that Brown wrote over the years, 1984 (Box 42, Folder 9)
  - Professional Writings:"Pith and Vinegar" - a collection of epigrams, aphorisms, maxims, proverbs, etc, that Brown wrote over the years, 1984 (Box 42, Folder 10)
  - Professional Writings:"Pith and Vinegar" - a collection of epigrams, aphorisms, maxims, proverbs, etc, that Brown wrote over the years, 1984 (Box 42, Folder 11)
  - Professional Writings (Box 43)
  - Professional Writings:"Pith and Vinegar" - a collection of epigrams, aphorisms, maxims, proverbs, etc, that Brown wrote over the years (continued), 1987 (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Professional Writings:"Pith and Vinegar" - a collection of epigrams, aphorisms, maxims, proverbs, etc, that Brown wrote over the years (continued), 1987 (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Professional Writings:"Pith and Vinegar" - a collection of epigrams, aphorisms, maxims, proverbs, etc, that Brown wrote over the years (continued), 1987 (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - Professional Writings:Quotations relating to management, leadership, creativity, wisdom, bureaucracy, education, power, etc., undated (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Professional Writings:Quotations relating to management, leadership, creativity, wisdom, bureaucracy, education, power, etc., undated (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Professional Writings:Quotations relating to management, leadership, creativity, wisdom, bureaucracy, education, power, etc., undated (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - Professional Writings:Quotations relating to management, leadership, creativity, wisdom, bureaucracy, education, power, etc., undated (Box 43, Folder 7)
  - Professional Writings:Quotations relating to management, leadership, creativity, wisdom, bureaucracy, education, power, etc., undated (Box 43, Folder 8)
  - Professional Writings:Quotations relating to management, leadership, creativity, wisdom, bureaucracy, education, power, etc., undated (Box 43, Folder 9)
  - Professional Writings:Quotations relating to management, leadership, creativity, wisdom, bureaucracy, education, power, etc., undated (Box 43, Folder 10)
  - Professional Writings:Quotations relating to management, leadership, creativity, wisdom, bureaucracy, education, power, etc., undated (Box 43, Folder 11)
  - Professional Writings:Quotations relating to management, leadership, creativity, wisdom, bureaucracy, education, power, etc., undated (Box 43, Folder 12)
  - Professional Writings:Quotations relating to management, leadership, creativity, wisdom, bureaucracy, education, power, etc., undated (Box 43, Folder 13)
  - Professional Writings:Quotations relating to management, leadership, creativity, wisdom, bureaucracy, education, power, etc., undated (Box 43, Folder 14)
  - Professional Writings:Quotations relating to management, leadership, creativity, wisdom, bureaucracy, education, power, etc., undated (Box 43, Folder 15)
  - Professional Writings:Quotations relating to management, leadership, creativity, wisdom, bureaucracy, education, power, etc., undated (Box 43, Folder 16)
  - Professional Writings:Quotations relating to management, leadership, creativity, wisdom, bureaucracy, education, power, etc., undated (Box 43, Folder 17)
  - Professional Writings:Quotations relating to management, leadership, creativity, wisdom, bureaucracy, education, power, etc., undated (Box 43, Folder 18)
  - Professional Writings:Quotations relating to management, leadership, creativity, wisdom, bureaucracy, education, power, etc., undated (Box 43, Folder 19)
  - Professional Writings:Quotations relating to management, leadership, creativity, wisdom, bureaucracy, education, power, etc., undated (Box 43, Folder 20)
  - Professional Writings:Quotations relating to management, leadership, creativity, wisdom, bureaucracy, education, power, etc., undated (Box 43, Folder 21)
  - Professional Writings:Quotations relating to management, leadership, creativity, wisdom, bureaucracy, education, power, etc., undated (Box 43, Folder 22)
  - Professional Writings:Quotations relating to management, leadership, creativity, wisdom, bureaucracy, education, power, etc., undated (Box 43, Folder 23)
  - Professional Writings:Quotations relating to management, leadership, creativity, wisdom, bureaucracy, education, power, etc., undated (Box 43, Folder 24)
  - Professional Writings:Quotations relating to management, leadership, creativity, wisdom, bureaucracy, education, power, etc., undated (Box 43, Folder 25)
  - Professional Writings:Quotations relating to management, leadership, creativity, wisdom, bureaucracy, education, power, etc., undated (Box 43, Folder 26)
  - Professional Writings:Quotations relating to management, leadership, creativity, wisdom, bureaucracy, education, power, etc., undated (Box 43, Folder 27)
  - Professional Writings (Box 44)
  - Professional Writings:Quotations relating to management, leadership, creativity, wisdom, bureaucracy, education, power, etc., undated (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Professional Writings:Quotations relating to management, leadership, creativity, wisdom, bureaucracy, education, power, etc., undated (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - Professional Writings:Quotations relating to management, leadership, creativity, wisdom, bureaucracy, education, power, etc., undated (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - Professional Writings:Quotations relating to management, leadership, creativity, wisdom, bureaucracy, education, power, etc., undated (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - Professional Writings:Quotations relating to management, leadership, creativity, wisdom, bureaucracy, education, power, etc., undated (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - Professional Writings:Quotations relating to management, leadership, creativity, wisdom, bureaucracy, education, power, etc., undated (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - Professional Writings:Quotations relating to management, leadership, creativity, wisdom, bureaucracy, education, power, etc., undated (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - Professional Writings:Articles on humor and wit, undated (Box 44, Folder 8)
  - Professional Writings:Articles on humor and wit, undated (Box 44, Folder 9)
  - Professional Writings:Articles on humor and wit, undated (Box 44, Folder 10)
  - Professional Writings:Articles on humor and wit, undated (Box 44, Folder 11)
  - Professional Writings:Articles on humor and wit, undated (Box 44, Folder 12)
  - Professional Writings:Articles on humor and wit, undated (Box 44, Folder 13)
  - Professional Writings:Articles on humor and wit, undated (Box 44, Folder 14)
- Scrapbooks, 1915-1985; MS0001 Series 11; 50 Linear feet
  This series contains scrapbooks of clippings, photographs, letters, and memorabilia primarily documenting David S. Brown's family life from his birth in 1915 through 1985.
  - Scrapbook 1, 1915-1936 (Box 45)
    A green scrapbook (15" x 12" x 2.5") containing records of David S. Brown's life from birth through a graduation from the University of Maine. Family trees, photographs of relatives and childhood photographs are included. From Brown's high school and college years are letters, papers written for classes, oratorical awards, early bylines and certificates of graduation and promotion. Of historical significance are a 1927 photograph of Charles E. Lindbergh on a postcard, newspaper clippings on the subject of the New Deal, and a personal letter to Brown from Maine Congressman Brewster.
  - Scrapbook 2, 1936-1942 (Box 46)
    A brown scrapbook (14.5" x 12.25" x 1.5") containing photographs, newspaper clippings and letters to family members from Brown during his days as a student and teacher at Syracuse University and as a Navy pilot. A certificate is included which establishes Brown as a "Challenger" for the Democratic Party in the 1936 New York State elections. Of historical interest is the front page section of The Corpus Christi Caller - Times from January 17, 1943 with the lead story; "140,000 Nazis Slaughtered at Stalingrad: U.S. Planes Shoot Down 30 Jap Planes, Blast Four Ships".
  - Scrapbook 3, 1942-1944 (Box 47)
    A maroon scrapbook (12" x 9" x 2.5") containing photographs, newspaper clippings, letters and telegrams to Brown from Evelyn Lovett and to Lovett from Brown chronicling the couple's courtship and marriage. Several volumes of a satirical paper written by Brown while in the Navy are included. The Weekly Constitution (later called The Weekly Constitutional) includes volume I numbers 1-7 and volume III numbers 1 5. The birth of the Brown's first child, David Springer Brown, Jr. on March 7, 1944 is also recorded through announcements.
  - Scrapbook 4, 1943-1944 (Box 48)
    A green scrapbook (11.75" x 9.5" x 1.75") chronicling, through photographs, the Brown's wedding and first year of marriage. Of historical interest are an unused war ration book, a pamphlet illustrating U.S. Army, Navy and Marine Corps insignia and medals and an 8" x 10" black and white photograph of Mrs. Brown's father, Robert A. Lovette who was then the Secretary of War For Air. Also included is the cover of the May 1944 edition of Wings magazine featuring Lovett.
  - Scrapbook 5, 03/1944 --09/1944 (Box 48)
    This red scrapbook (11.25" x 9.25" x 0.25") contains newspaper clippings from the Navy Air Services (NAS) Skywriter of a column written by Brown while in the Navy. The column, "Have You Heard", collected quotations by various Navy personnel in a humorous format. Noteworthy are articles from Skywriter that detail various downings, crashes or disappearances of Navy pilots. Airmen mentioned include, Captain Donald E. McCafferty and Lieutenant (jg) John W. Sebek. Also from Skywriter are articles detailing the promotion of Lieutenant Commander Frank A. Patriarca and Lieutenant Commander Raymond P. Kline.
  - Scrapbook 5A, 10/1943 --03/1944 (Box 48)
    This cream-colored scrapbook (11.25" x 8.25" x 0.5") was originally part of scrapbook number 5 and contains more articles from NAS Miami Skywriter written by Brown as well as his column "Have You Heard". Of special interest is a United States Navy Naval Aviator certificate from 1943.
  - Scrapbook 6, 10/1946 --12/31/1946 (Box 49)
    A green, brown, cream and red woven cover scrapbook (15" X 12.75" x 1") containing newspaper clippings from the Bangor Daily News of Brown's column "Maine Live from Washington" detailing news from Washington, D.C. pertaining to Maine. Of historical interest is a page from the Congressional Record Appendix (p. 19097) with the text of two speeches "How to Murder a Democracy" given by the Honorable Gerald P. Nye of North Dakota, and "Public Opinion Polls and the Maine Election" given by the Honorable Walter M. Pierce of Oregon, both in September 1940. The later is particularly important as it deals with the implications of the use of the Gallup Opinion Polls to predict outcomes of elections. Also included in this scrapbook is the text of a speech delivered by Brown at Stephens College in Columbia, Missouri during a conference on "Women in Aviation" in May 1946. Brown chronicles the life of Mrs. Phoebe Fairgrave Omlie, a pioneer among women aviators.
  - Scrapbook 7, 10/1944 --08/1947 (Box 50)